Preliminary guide to the James Goode papers, Circa 1860-2018 MS0670.UA
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
James Goode papers
circa 1860-2018
1950-2018
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Goode, James M., 1939-2019
MS0670.UA
66.5 Linear Feet
The collection include manuscript drafts and proofs, research notes, clippings, photographs, prints, correspondence, awards, lecture notes, personal papers, professional papers, and reports. They range in date from circa 1860 to 2017, but the bulk of the material dates from 1950 to 2011. The material relates to James Goode's graduate studies, his 2009 book on Washington sculptures, his collection of American self-portraits, his personal and professional life, and other research interests.
Acquisition Information
This collection was donated to the University Archives by Dr. Goode in 1997. A second donation was made in 2007 (Accession 2007.027) and other donations were made in 2009 (Accession 2009.13 and 2009.25). Another donation was made in 2016 (Accession 2016.120).The material from this donation is housed in boxes 109, 110, and 111. Another donation was made in 2017 (accession 2017.043). That material is mostly housed in boxes 112, 113, and 114 (with two oversize items added to an existing box). Another donation was made in December 2017 (accession 2017.076) and was added to boxes 115-116.
Biographical Note
James Moore Goode (1939-2019) is the author of numerous books relating to Washington, D.C. history, and earned his Ph.D. from The George Washington University in 1995. Dr. Goode was born September 17, 1939 in Stateville, North Carolina. He graduated with a B.A. from the University of South Carolina in 1964 and an M.A. from the University of Virginia in 1966. From 1966-68 he was an instructor at George Mason University, teaching undergraduate courses in American and European history. From there he went to the Library of Congress, working in the Prints and Photographs Division from 1968-70, providing reference services for researchers.
From 1970-1988 he served as Curator for the Smithsonian Institution Building, and he was responsible for planning, organizing, and directing an extensive restorations to the historic Castle building built between 1847 and 1855. He also prepared and presented lectures and tours of the building for scholars, docents, and the general public, and organized exhibits.
Beginning in 1988, he worked as a consultant in fine arts and architectural history, and served on the board of directors for two historic house museums: the Ruthmere in Elkhart, Indiana, and the Decatur House in Washington, D.C. During that time he researched and prepared five exhibitions for the Kiplinger Washington Editors art gallery, including Washington During the Civil War and Two Hundred Years of White House History, and one for the National Building Museum, based on his book "Best Addresses, One Hundred Years of Washington's Distinguished Apartment Houses."
Dr. Goode is the author of several books, including the aforementioned "Best Addresses" (1988), "Capital Losses: A Cultural History of Washington's Destroyed Buildings" (1979), "The Outdoor Sculpture of Washington, D.C." (1974), and Washington Scuplture (2009). A 300 photograph collection for his dissertation "Architecture and Politics: Thomas Ustick Walter and the Enlargement of the U.S. Capitol, 1850-65" was donated to the archives of the American Institute of Architects in 1996.
On May 27, 2015 Dr. Goode was presented the "Visionary Historian" award by The Historical Society of Washington D.C.
Dr. Goode was a member of numerous associations, and at one time served on the boards of the Historical Society of Washington, the Victorian Society of America, and the White House Historical Society.
The Library of Congress, University of Virginia Archive, and the Smithsonian Institute also have collections of papers related to James Goode.
James Moore Goode passed away on December 12, 2019 following a brief illness.
Collection Scope and Contents note
The materials of this collection include manuscript drafts and proofs, research notes, clippings, photographs, prints, correspondence, framed awards, diplomas, brochures, lecture notes, diaries, checking account ledgers, address books, appointment books, newspapers and magazines, school papers, personal records, organizational records, readings, exams, and reports. They range in date from 1903 to 2017, but the bulk of the material dates from 1950 to 2011.
Separated Material note
The following books have been separated from the collection and are kept in the Special Collections book collection: James M. Goode. Washington Sculpture: A Cultural History of Outdoor Sculpture in the Nation's Capital. The Johns Hopkins University Press, 2009. James M. Goode. Outdoor Sculpture of Washington D.C. Smithsonian Books, 1979. Capital Houses historic Residences of Washington D.C. and its Environs 1735, 1965 by James Goode. Capital Views Historic Photographs of Washington D.C., Alexandria and Loundoun County, Virginia and Frederick County, Maryland by James Goode. Three Centuries of the American Bookplate by James Goode The B.F. Saul Company Real Estate and Finance in the Nation's Capital Since 1892 by James Goode.
Arrangement note
Organized into eight series: Graduate studies, Washington Sculpture, American self-portraits, Kennedy-Warren Apartment House, Photographs, slides and framed awards, Personal papers, Professional papers, and Correspondence.
Materials at another repository
The Smithsonian Institution Archives contains some biographical materials for Dr. Goode. These include:
Smithsonian Institution Archives Coll. No. 420 Box 5 Folder 24 (contains For the press clippings:)
Smithsonian Institution Archives Coll. No. 95-085 Box 2 Folder: "Goode,James 1987-90" (contains: the S. Dillon Ripley personal file on Dr. Goode, including a summary of Dr. Goode's career up to that point, and Mr. Ripley's draft letters of recommendation for Dr. Goode's application to graduate school)
United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865; Washington (D.C.); Photographs; American civilization; Washington (D.C.) -- History; Exhibitions; Biography; Architecture -- Washington (D.C.); Historic buildings -- Conservation and restoration; George Washington University--Alumni and alumnae; George Washington University; Smithsonian Institution
- Undergraduate and graduate studies, 1964-1995; 1987-1991; Series 1; 4 Linear Feet
  Scope and Content note
  Materials in this series include a C.V., lecture notes, readings, exams, and other materials from Dr. James Goode's doctoral program in American Studies at GW. They range in date from 1964-1995, but most material dates from 1987 to 1991.
  Arrangement note
  Arranged into binders according to courses and subject.
  - American Civ. 175, US Archaeology History - 1600-1860, Fall 1870: 175 Arch. Hist. 1600 - 1860, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
    General note
    Note: in binder 1
  - American Civ. 175, US Archaeology History - 1600-1860, Fall 1870: 175 Arch. 175 Lectures - Longstreth, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - American Civ. 175, US Archaeology History - 1600-1860, Fall 1870: 175 Arch. 175 Reading -, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - American Civ. 175, US Archaeology History - 1600-1860, Fall 1870: 175 Arch. 175 Grad Semester, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - American Civ. 175, US Archaeology History - 1600-1860, Fall 1870: 175 Arch. 175 Grad Reading, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - American Civ. 175, US Archaeology History - 1600-1860, Fall 1870: 175 Arch. 175 Syllabus, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - American Civ. 175, US Archaeology History - 1600-1860, Fall 1870: 175 Arch. Andrews, Deborah C. (Bank Buildings in 19th Century Philadelphia), undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - American Civ. 175, US Archaeology History - 1600-1860, Fall 1870: 175 Arch. Blackwar, Betsy (Rewalking the "Walking city" Housing and Property Relations in NY city 1780-1840), undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - American Civ. 175, US Archaeology History - 1600-1860, Fall 1870: 175 Arch. Bishir, Jay E (A Monument of Trade), undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - American Civ. 175, US Archaeology History - 1600-1860, Fall 1870: 175 Arch. Brugemann, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - American Civ. 175, US Archaeology History - 1600-1860, Fall 1870: 175 Arch. Cantor, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - American Civ. 175, US Archaeology History - 1600-1860, Fall 1870: 175 Arch. Carson, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - American Civ. 175, US Archaeology History - 1600-1860, Fall 1870: 175 Arch. Condit, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - American Civ. 175, US Archaeology History - 1600-1860, Fall 1870: 175 Arch. Gowans, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - American Civ. 175, US Archaeology History - 1600-1860, Fall 1870: 175 Arch. Herman, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - American Civ. 175, US Archaeology History - 1600-1860, Fall 1870: 175 Arch. Kniffen Glassie, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - American Civ. 175, US Archaeology History - 1600-1860, Fall 1870: 175 Arch. Peterson, E., undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - American Civ. 175, US Archaeology History - 1600-1860, Fall 1870: 175 Arch. Longstreth, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - American Civ. 175, US Archaeology History - 1600-1860, Fall 1870: 175 Arch. Kniffen, undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - American Civ. 175, US Archaeology History - 1600-1860, Fall 1870: 175 Arch. Kinney Workman, undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - American Civ. 175, US Archaeology History - 1600-1860, Fall 1870: 175 Arch. Pierson 1, undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - American Civ. 175, US Archaeology History - 1600-1860, Fall 1870: 175 Arch. Upton, undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - American Civ. 175, US Archaeology History - 1600-1860, Fall 1870: 175 Arch. Roberts, undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - American Civ. 175, US Archaeology History - 1600-1860, Fall 1870: 175 Arch. Shapiro, Meyer (Style), undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - American Civ. 175, US Archaeology History - 1600-1860, Fall 1870: 175 Arch. Pierson 2, undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - James M. Goode, 186 Urban History (Research Notebook), 1920s: (A)Builder - C.P. Barrett; Area - 12 & FLVA, Ave. NW, Location - 1154 - 1164 Neal St. N.E. (4th, April 195), 01/1988 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    Note: in binder 2
  - James M. Goode, 186 Urban History (Research Notebook), 1920s: (C)Agent - Floyd E. Davis, Area: Petworth. Exhibit - 4914 Illinois Ave., N.W. (31, Jan, 1925), 01/1988 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - James M. Goode, 186 Urban History (Research Notebook), 1920s: (D)Builder - H.L England, Location: 7542, 12 St, NW - (18 man, 1929), 01/1988 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - James M. Goode, 186 Urban History (Research Notebook), 1920s: (E)Builder - J.E. Fox, Location: 5242 - 5244 Colorado Ave. NW, 01/1988 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - James M. Goode, 186 Urban History (Research Notebook), 1920s: (F)Garage - 1920s, 01/1988 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - James M. Goode, 186 Urban History (Research Notebook), 1920s: (B)Builder - Morris Cafritz. Exhibit Houses - 835 Decatur St. N.W. 4825 Illinois Ave, N.W., 01/1988 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - James M. Goode, 186 Urban History (Research Notebook), 1920s: (G)Builder - Hedge & Middleton (Agent) HE - 1920, Location: 760-782 Irving St. N.W., 01/1988 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - James M. Goode, 186 Urban History (Research Notebook), 1920s: (H), 01/1988 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - James M. Goode, 186 Urban History (Research Notebook), 1920s: (I)Builder - J. J. James, Location: 730-738 Rittenhaure St. N.W. - 30 May 1925, 01/1988 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - James M. Goode, 186 Urban History (Research Notebook), 1920s: (J)Builder - Kay Schnider, Model House: 819 Delafield St. NW 12th Jan, 1925, 01/1988 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - James M. Goode, 186 Urban History (Research Notebook), 1920s: (K)Agent: Arthur Lewey. Exhibit House: 311 Allison St., NW, 01/1988 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - James M. Goode, 186 Urban History (Research Notebook), 1920s: (L)Builder: Maddux, Marshall & Co. Row Houses Built to Order. 28th Feb, 1925, 01/1988 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - James M. Goode, 186 Urban History (Research Notebook), 1920s: (Mc) Builder: McKeever & Goss. Area: Chevy Chase, D.C. Location: Conn. Ave., 01/1988 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - James M. Goode, 186 Urban History (Research Notebook), 1920s: (M)Builder: Nat. Mortgatge & Invest Corp. Model: 5519 4st, NW, 01/1988 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - James M. Goode, 186 Urban History (Research Notebook), 1920s: (N)Agent: John J. O'Connor. Area: North Cleveland Park. Exhibit House: 3716 Windom Pl. NW, 01/1988 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - James M. Goode, 186 Urban History (Research Notebook), 1920s: (O)Builder: D.J. Partelle. Location: 4016-4022 GA Ave. NW 29th May 1920, 01/1988 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - James M. Goode, 186 Urban History (Research Notebook), 1920s: (P)(blank), 01/1988 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - James M. Goode, 186 Urban History (Research Notebook), 1920s: (Q)Agent: Percy H Russell Co. 18 May 1929, 01/1988 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - James M. Goode, 186 Urban History (Research Notebook), 1920s: (R)Builder: N.L Sansbury Co. Location: 5700-57200 8th St. NW 19th Dec 1925, 01/1988 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - James M. Goode, 186 Urban History (Research Notebook), 1920s: (S)Agent: J.B. Tiffey. Location: 5th & Oneida ST. NW, 01/1988 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - James M. Goode, 186 Urban History (Research Notebook), 1920s: (T)(blank), 01/1988 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - James M. Goode, 186 Urban History (Research Notebook), 1920s: (U)(blank), 01/1988 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - James M. Goode, 186 Urban History (Research Notebook), 1920s: (V)Builder: Maggaman & Brawner. Location: 321-327 Channing St. NE 7th Mar 1925, 01/1988 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - James M. Goode, 186 Urban History (Research Notebook), 1920s: (XYZ) Builder: Joseph C. Zirkle. Area: Wash. Heights Location: 1855 & 1857 Calif ST. NW, 01/1988 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - AMER CIV 176 - U.S Arch History 1860 - Present, Spring Semester: Lectures, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 50)
    Note: in binder 3
  - AMER CIV 176 - U.S Arch History 1860 - Present, Spring Semester: Readings, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - AMER CIV 176 - U.S Arch History 1860 - Present, Spring Semester: Bibliography, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - AMER CIV 176 - U.S Arch History 1860 - Present, Spring Semester: Graduate Readings, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - AMER CIV 176 - U.S Arch History 1860 - Present, Spring Semester: Week 1-2 (High Victorian Gothic; The Dilemma of Syle in Modern Architecture), 1988 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - AMER CIV 176 - U.S Arch History 1860 - Present, Spring Semester: Week 3 (The making of Richardson Building 1874-1886), 1988 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - AMER CIV 176 - U.S Arch History 1860 - Present, Spring Semester: Week 4 (Central Heating & Forced Ventilation: Origins and Effects on Architectural Design), 1988 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - AMER CIV 176 - U.S Arch History 1860 - Present, Spring Semester: Week 5 (office buildings & organizational change), 1988 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - AMER CIV 176 - U.S Arch History 1860 - Present, Spring Semester: Week 6 (Academic Eclecticism in American Architecture), 1988 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - AMER CIV 176 - U.S Arch History 1860 - Present, Spring Semester: Week 7 (The Moderne in the US 1920-1941), 1988 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - AMER CIV 176 - U.S Arch History 1860 - Present, Spring Semester: Week 8, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - AMER CIV 176 - U.S Arch History 1860 - Present, Spring Semester: Week 9 (Craftman Style and Technostyle), 1988 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - AMER CIV 176 - U.S Arch History 1860 - Present, Spring Semester: Week 10 (The Architecture of Urban Housing in the US during early 1930s, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - AMER CIV 176 - U.S Arch History 1860 - Present, Spring Semester: Week 11 - 14 Reports (Twenties Gothic), 1988 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - AMER CIV 176 - U.S Arch History 1860 - Present, Spring Semester: Slides, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - AMER CIV 176 - U.S Arch History 1860 - Present, Spring Semester: Termpaper, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - AMCV 379. US Cultural History, Fall Semester: Class Notes, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 66)
    Note: in binder 4
  - AMCV 379. US Cultural History, Fall Semester: Reference, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - AMCV 379. US Cultura History, Fall Semester: Bryce, James "The American Commonwealth", 1989 (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - AMCV 379. US Cultural History, Fall Semester: Curti, Merle "The Growth of American Thought" NY: 1943, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - AMCV 379. US Cultural History, Fall Semester: Gabriel, Ralph "The Course of American", 1989 (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - AMCV 379. US Cultural History, Fall Semester: Lipset, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - AMCV 379. US Cultural History, Fall Semester: Parrington, Vernon L., 1989 (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - AMCV 379. US Cultural History, Fall Semester: Potter, David, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - AMCV 379. US Cultural History, Fall Semester: Riesman, David, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - AMCV 379. US Cultural History, Fall Semester: Tocqueville, " Democracy in America", 1989 (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - AMCV 379. US Cultural History, Fall Semester: Turner, Frederick Johnson (NY: 1921), 1989 (Box 1, Folder 76)
  - AMCV 379. US Cultural History, Fall Semester: B.Franklin, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - AMCV 379. US Cultural History, Fall Semester: Van Doren, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - AMCV 379. US Cultural History, Fall Semester: DAB, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 79)
  - AMCV 379. US Cultural History, Fall Semester: Rapson, Richard L., 1989 (Box 1, Folder 80)
  - AMCV 379. US Cultural History, Fall Semester: History, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 81)
  - AMCV 379. US Cultural History, Fall Semester: Trial Exam - Outline, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 82)
  - AMCV 379. US Cultural History, Fall Semester: Final Exam - Outline, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 83)
  - History 398. 18th Century England. Fall Semester: Reading List, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - History 398. 18th Century England. Fall Semester: Marshall, Dorothy "18th Century England, 1962", 1989 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - History 398. 18th Century England. Fall Semester: Porter, Roy "English Society in the 18th Century, 1982", 1989 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - History 398. 18th Century England. Fall Semester: Girouaad, Mark "Life in the English Country House (1978) a social & architectural history, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - History 398. 18th Century England. Fall Semester: George, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - History 398. 18th Century England. Fall Semester: Richardson, A.E, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - History 398. 18th Century England. Fall Semester: Fleming, John "Robert Adam and His Circle in Edinburgh and Rome"1962, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - History 398. 18th Century England. Fall Semester: Yarwood, Dorean 1970, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - History 398. 18th Century England. Fall Semester: Brooke, John "King George III, America's Last March" NY: 1972, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - History 398. 18th Century England. Fall Semester: White, R.J. "The Age of Gedye III", 1989 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - History 398. 18th Century England. Fall Semester: Ison, Walter - London 1948, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - History 398. 18th Century England. Fall Semester: Cunliffe, Barry "The City of Bath" Yale 1986, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - History 398. 18th Century England. Fall Semester: Foss, Michael "The Age of Pat" 1971, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - History 398. 18th Century England. Fall Semester: Laslett, Peter "The World We Have Lost" 1965, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - History 398. 18th Century England. Fall Semester: Canon, John "Aristocratic Century The passage of 18th Century England" 1984, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - History 398. 18th Century England. Fall Semester: Du Prey, Pierre "The making of an Architect" 1982, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - 252 and 253, Material Culture American Studies Dept: 253 Outline, 1988-1990 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - 252 and 253, Material Culture American Studies Dept: 253 Class, 1988-1990 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - 252 and 253, Material Culture American Studies Dept: Berry, Michael W "Regional American Silver", 1988-1990 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - 252 and 253, Material Culture American Studies Dept: Braudel 20th September, 1988-1990 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - 252 and 253, Material Culture American Studies Dept: Bushman, 1988-1990 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - 252 and 253, Material Culture American Studies Dept: Cooke, 1988-1990 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - 252 and 253, Material Culture American Studies Dept: Cooper 22nd, September, 1988-1990 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - 252 and 253, Material Culture American Studies Dept: Deetz, James 13 September "In Small Things Forgotten", 1988-1990 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - 252 and 253, Material Culture American Studies Dept: Ettema, Michael J. - 13th September "Forum", 1988-1990 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - 252 and 253, Material Culture American Studies Dept: Fleming, E. McClung - 27th September "Artifact Study: A proposed Model", 1988-1990 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - 252 and 253, Material Culture American Studies Dept: Forman, Benno M. - 4th October "American Seating Furniture 1630-1730, 1988-1990 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - 252 and 253, Material Culture American Studies Dept: Glassie, 1988-1990 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - 252 and 253, Material Culture American Studies Dept: Hewitt, Benjamin - 11th October "The walk of Many Hands", 1988-1990 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - 252 and 253, Material Culture American Studies Dept: Hodder, Ian - 13th September "Reading the Past", 1988-1990 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - 252 and 253, Material Culture American Studies Dept: Hodder - 27th September "Art Decoration & Style", 1988-1990 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - 252 and 253, Material Culture American Studies Dept: Miller, George L. "Marketing Ceramics in North America", 1988-1990 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - 252 and 253, Material Culture American Studies Dept: Mitchell, 1988-1990 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - 252 and 253, Material Culture American Studies Dept: Montgomery, 1988-1990 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - 252 and 253, Material Culture American Studies Dept: 19th Century Furn., 1988-1990 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - 252 and 253, Material Culture American Studies Dept: Horowitz, 1988-1990 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - 252 and 253, Material Culture American Studies Dept: Price, 1988-1990 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - 252 and 253, Material Culture American Studies Dept: Powan 13th September, 1988-1990 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - 252 and 253, Material Culture American Studies Dept: Powan 27th September, 1988-1990 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - 252 and 253, Material Culture American Studies Dept: Rosenberg, 1988-1990 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - 252 and 253, Material Culture American Studies Dept: Stewart 27th September, 1988-1990 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - 252 and 253, Material Culture American Studies Dept: Trewt 27th September, 1988-1990 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - 252 and 253, Material Culture American Studies Dept: Sugden 4th October, 1988-1990 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - 252 and 253, Material Culture American Studies Dept: Project, 1988-1990 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - AMCV 380 U.S. Cultural History, Spring Semester: Class Notes, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - AMCV 380 U.S. Cultural History, Spring Semester: Bibliography, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - AMCV 380 U.S. Cultural History, Spring Semester: Outline, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - AMCV 380 U.S. Cultural History, Spring Semester: Architecture (Milton Brown - American Art), 1990 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - AMCV 380 U.S. Cultural History, Spring Semester: Art (Milton Brown - American Art: paintings, Sculpture, Architecture, Decorative Arts, Photography), 1990 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - AMCV 380 U.S. Cultural History, Spring Semester: City Planning (Joseph Arnold, Walker ), 1990 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - AMCV 380 U.S. Cultural History, Spring Semester: Education, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - AMCV 380 U.S. Cultural History, Spring Semester: Historiography, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - AMCV 380 U.S. Cultural History, Spring Semester: Immigration, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - AMCV 380 U.S. Cultural History, Spring Semester: Labor Mov. (Edward Peason, Most Uncommon Josh) 1967, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 54)